[{"question":" Scala bytecode can run on top of Java VM. What is the fundamental difference between Java object.clone() and Scala object.copy()?","options":[{"text":"One is a Java object, the other is a Scala object.","correct":false},{"text":"clone() will copy class structures but not the data, while copy() will also copy data into new objects.","correct":false},{"text":"There is no difference.","correct":false},{"text":"copy() allows you to change values during the copying process; clone() does not.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What value does this code return?","options":[{"text":"a","correct":false},{"text":"2","correct":false},{"text":"b","correct":false},{"text":"1","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\nval m1 = Map(\"a\"->1,\"b\"->2,\"c\"->3)\nm1(\"a\")\n```"},{"question":" What is one way to avoid low-level parallelization details?","options":[{"text":"monads","correct":false},{"text":"literal functions","correct":false},{"text":"partially applied functions","correct":false},{"text":"parallel collections","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What do you use in ScalaTest to see a detailed diagram of error messages when a test fails?","options":[{"text":"ArgumentExceptions","correct":false},{"text":"AssertionException","correct":false},{"text":"DiagrammedAssertions","correct":true},{"text":"JUnit","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What data type would you use to store an immutable collection of objects that contain a fixed number of varying types?","options":[{"text":"Array","correct":false},{"text":"ImmutableCollection","correct":false},{"text":"List","correct":false},{"text":"Tuple","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" After defining a function in the interpreter, Scala returns the following. What does the","options":[{"text":"The function has no side effects.","correct":false},{"text":"The function takes no parameters.","correct":false},{"text":"The function returns no value.","correct":true},{"text":"Returning unit types to the function is a closures.","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nmyfnc: ()Unit\n```"},{"question":" What type of number is 1234.e5?","options":[{"text":"hexadecimal","correct":false},{"text":"short","correct":false},{"text":"floating point","correct":true},{"text":"long","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" When you convert a map to a list using the toList method of the map, the result will be of which type?","options":[{"text":"`List[(String, String)]`","correct":false},{"text":"`List[(Array, Array)]`","correct":false},{"text":"`List[(Array, Array)]`","correct":false},{"text":"`List`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What type of object does this code create?","options":[{"text":"List","correct":false},{"text":"Map","correct":false},{"text":"Tuple","correct":true},{"text":"Array","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nval x = (1234, \"Active\")\n```"},{"question":". Which is a subclass of all classes?","options":[{"text":"AnyVal","correct":false},{"text":"AnyRef","correct":false},{"text":"Method","correct":false},{"text":"Null NOT SURE","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". For the for-yield construct, is the scope separate between for-body and yield-body?","options":[{"text":"Yes and no. It is different depending on the for construct and what it does. NOT SURE","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, because the for section does not expose its scope.","correct":false},{"text":"No, because for-yield shares the same scope, even though they are within separate curly braces.","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, because they are within different curly braces.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is one way to implement pattern matching on methods?","options":[{"text":"using regex","correct":false},{"text":"using monads","correct":false},{"text":"using string matching","correct":true},{"text":"using case classes","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the value of z after executing this code?","options":[{"text":"List(a,b,c)","correct":false},{"text":"List(List(a, b), c)","correct":true},{"text":"List(c,a,b)","correct":false},{"text":"List(c,List(a,b))","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nval y = List('a','b')\nval z = y::List('c')\n```"},{"question":". What term is used to specify a precondition?","options":[{"text":"assert","correct":true},{"text":"require","correct":false},{"text":"precondition","correct":false},{"text":"mustHave","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which Scala type may throw an exception or a successfully computed value, and is commonly used to trap and propagate errors?","options":[{"text":"`scala.util.ExceptionHandling`","correct":false},{"text":"`scala.Catch.Throw`","correct":false},{"text":"`scala.exception.TryFinally`","correct":false},{"text":"`scala.util.Try`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the data type of y after this code is executed?","options":[{"text":"short","correct":false},{"text":"double","correct":true},{"text":"int","correct":false},{"text":"bigInt","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nval y = (math floor 3.1415 * 2)\n```"},{"question":". When using pattern matching, which character matches on any object?","options":[{"text":"`%`","correct":false},{"text":"`\\_`","correct":false},{"text":"`^`","correct":false},{"text":"`-`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have created an array using val. Can you change the value of any element of the arrayâ€”and why or why not?","options":[{"text":"Yes, the reference to the array is immutable, so the location that the array points to is immutable. The values in the array are mutable.","correct":false},{"text":"The 0th element is immutable and cannot be modified. All other elements can be modified.","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, val does not make arrays immutable.","correct":true},{"text":"No, val makes the array and values of the array immutable.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the output of this function?","options":[{"text":"1,2,3,4,5","correct":false},{"text":"0,1,2,3,4","correct":false},{"text":"1,2,3,4","correct":true},{"text":"2,3,4,5","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\ndef main () {\n     var a = 0\n     for (a<-1 until 5){println(a)}\n```"},{"question":". What do you call objects with immutable state?","options":[{"text":"singletons","correct":true},{"text":"stationary objects","correct":false},{"text":"functional objects","correct":false},{"text":"fixed objects","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have written a Scala script. How would you access command-line arguments in the script?","options":[{"text":"use array named args","correct":true},{"text":"use tuple named args","correct":false},{"text":"use numbered variables with a _ prefix for example _ 1, _ 2, _ 3","correct":false},{"text":"use numbered variables with a $ prefix - for example $1, $2, $3","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does this code return? val x = 3; if (x >2) x = 4 else x = x\\*2","options":[{"text":"4","correct":false},{"text":"an error","correct":true},{"text":"6","correct":false},{"text":"3","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement returns a success or a failure indicator when you execute this code?","options":[{"text":"myFuture.onComplete","correct":true},{"text":"myFuture(status)","correct":false},{"text":"myFuture.Finished","correct":false},{"text":"complete(myFuture)","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To denote a parameter that may be repeated, what should you place after type?","options":[{"text":"`%`","correct":false},{"text":"`&`","correct":false},{"text":"`\\_`","correct":false},{"text":"`-`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is called when a superclass has more than one subclass in Scala?","options":[{"text":"polyinheritance","correct":false},{"text":"multilevel inheritance","correct":false},{"text":"multimode inheritance","correct":false},{"text":"hierarchical inheritance","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". One way to improve code reliability is to use **\\_**, which will evaluate a condition and return an error if the conditions is violated.","options":[{"text":"packages","correct":false},{"text":"polymorphisms","correct":false},{"text":"assertions","correct":true},{"text":"traits","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement about if-else-if-else statements is true?","options":[{"text":"If the first else-if does not succeed, then no other else-ifs are tested.","correct":false},{"text":"If an else-if does not succeed, then none of the remaining else-if statements or elses will be tested.","correct":false},{"text":"All else-if statements are tested in all cases.","correct":false},{"text":"If an else-if succeeds, then none of the remaining else-if statements or elses will tested.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What do you call the process of changing the definition of an inherited method?","options":[{"text":"recursive methods","correct":false},{"text":"currying methods","correct":false},{"text":"redefining methods","correct":false},{"text":"overriding methods","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is an advantage of an immutable object?","options":[{"text":"Immutable objects use less memory than their mutable counterparts.","correct":false},{"text":"Immutable objects do not require error handling.","correct":false},{"text":"Immutable objects can be used in classes, mutable objects cannot.","correct":false},{"text":"Immutable objects are threadsafe.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the code below equivalent to?","options":[{"text":"myClass.foreach(println ())","correct":false},{"text":"myClass.foreach(print NIL)","correct":false},{"text":"myClass.loop(println ())","correct":false},{"text":"myClass.foreach(x => println(x))","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\nmyClass.foreach(println _)\n```"},{"question":". What is an advantage of an immutable object?","options":[{"text":"Immutable objects use less memory than their mutable counterparts.","correct":false},{"text":"Immutable objects do not require error handling.","correct":false},{"text":"Immutable objects can be used in classes, mutable objects cannot.","correct":false},{"text":"Immutable objects are threadsafe.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to create an iteration loop that tests the condition at the end of the loop body. Which iteration would you use?","options":[{"text":"do-while loop","correct":true},{"text":"while loop","correct":false},{"text":"for loop","correct":false},{"text":"do-until loop","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What can you use to make querying a database more efficient, by avoiding the need to parse the SQL string every time a query is executed from Scala?","options":[{"text":"database driver","correct":false},{"text":"connection","correct":false},{"text":"prepared statement","correct":false},{"text":"SQL view","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which is _not_ a member of the collections hierarchy?","options":[{"text":"Set","correct":false},{"text":"Seq","correct":false},{"text":"Hash","correct":true},{"text":"Map","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which term makes the contents of packages available without prefixing?","options":[{"text":"use","correct":false},{"text":"include","correct":false},{"text":"import","correct":true},{"text":"assertion","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". If you wanted to find the remainder after division, what operator would you use?","options":[{"text":"%","correct":true},{"text":"DIV","correct":false},{"text":"//","correct":false},{"text":"/","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What are defined inside a class definition?","options":[{"text":"method","correct":false},{"text":"fields and methods","correct":true},{"text":"fields, methods, and packages","correct":false},{"text":"fields","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What defines methods and fields that can then be reused by mixing into classes?","options":[{"text":"singleton","correct":false},{"text":"assertion","correct":false},{"text":"trait","correct":true},{"text":"monad","correct":false}],"illustrator":""}]